jennycraig.com 2019-05-26

# Privacy | Jenny Craig

## General

Many of the ways in which you interact with the Jenny Craig Web site ([www.jennycraig.com](http://www.jennycraig.com/) and [www.jennycraig.ca](http://www.jennycraig.ca/)) (each, a “Site”) and the Jenny Craig mobile app (the “App”) allow us to learn about you. This Privacy Statement describes the type of information we collect from you when you visit our Site or use our App and explains how Jenny Craig may use and disclose such information, as well as your ability to control certain uses of it.

## INFORMATION COLLECTION

### Information You Provide

Jenny Craig collects information from you when you choose to share it with us to use our Site or App, create an online account with us, request information from us, sign up for newsletters or our email list, post in our chat rooms or message boards, or otherwise contact us. The categories of information we collect are your name, physical address, email address, telephone number, photo/image, gender, date of birth, health information such as your current weight and goal weight, food consumption, and measurements, and, if you are a Jenny Craig customer, a credit/debit card number or other financial information including information about your purchases from us, as well as your Jenny ID which is assigned upon membership. If you access your account through our website, or if you use our App, we collect your user name and password. In addition, if you allow the App to have your location data, that data is only used to help you identify the nearest Jenny Craig Center. It is not stored. You have the option of choosing whether or not to reveal personally identifiable information to us. If you do not provide all “required” information, however, some portions of our Site or App will not work properly for you, or you will not be able to register or access certain sections of the Site. In the event of a complaint, we may also receive personally identifiable information about you from other parties or from other users or third parties who may communicate information to us about you in relation to that complaint. 

### Information Automatically Collected

We may use cookies, web beacons, log files, or other technologies to collect certain information about visitors to and users of our Sites and App, to deliver online advertisements that we think would be more relevant to your interests, and to monitor interactions with our emails and online advertisements. For example, we may automatically collect certain information from you, including but not limited to your browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, software version, and the domain name from which you accessed the Site or App. In addition, we may collect information about your browsing behavior, such as the date and time you visit the Site or App, the areas or pages of the Site or App that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing or using the Site or App, the number of times you return to the Site, other click-stream or Site or App usage data, and emails or ads that you open, forward or click-through to our Site or App.

Please note that our Sites use Google Analytics, a service that transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. Google Analytics does not identify individual users or visitors, nor does it associate users’ or visitors’ IP addresses with any other data held by Google. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage. In addition, we use Flurry, another analytics tool, to track statistics about downloads, frequency of use of our App, ratings, and similar metrics. Flurry does not collect your personally identifiable information.

### Cookies and Other Tracking Methods

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored on your hard drive when you visit our Site. We use cookies or, in a limited number of cases, IP addresses or other tracking tools, for a number of reasons. For example, these tools may (a) allow you to store your password without having to constantly re-enter it; (b) help us to tailor our Site or a marketing message to better match your needs and interests; and (c) allow us to better understand how you and others use our Site, which in turn helps us focus our resources on features that are the most popular. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, but some parts of our Site may not work properly if you do. Check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. To learn more about the use of cookies or other technologies to deliver more relevant advertising and to know your choices about not having this information used by certain Service Providers (defined below), please click [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

“Do-Not-Track” (“DNT”) is an optional browser setting that allows you to express your preferences regarding tracking by advertisers and other third-parties. When you choose to turn on the DNT setting in your browser, your browser sends a special signal to websites, ad networks, plug-in providers, and other web services you encounter while browsing to stop tracking your activity via cookies or other tracking technologies. We do not currently respond to Do-Not-Track browser signals or mechanisms. See the privacy policies of any linked sites with respect to how they respond to DNT signals, as their policies may differ from our own.

## Information from Other Sources

### Information Use

Jenny Craig may use the information we collect from and about you for any of the following purposes:

  * To operate our Site and App;
  * To enhance our Site and App;
  * To sell and deliver customized Site and App content, targeted offers and advertising on the Site or App, on other sites or apps, or via email;
  * To analyze our Site or App traffic and optimize how we lay out content on the Site or App;
  * To fulfill orders, provide service and communicate with customers;
  * To research and develop new products or services;
  * To post reviews of products and services our Site or App;
  * To respond to your inquiries;
  * To contact you with information, newsletters, and promotional materials from Jenny Craig;
  * To contact you when necessary;
  * To review the usage and operations of our Site or App and improve our content, products, and services;
  * To address problems with the Site, App, or our business;
  * To promote the Site or App;
  * To manage our telecommunications networks;
  * To protect the security or integrity of the Site, App, and our business;
  * As described to you at the point of data collection; and
  * To use and disclose your credit/debit card information only to process payments and prevent fraud.

We may combine the information you provide to us with information (1) from and about you that we automatically collect when you use Jenny Craig’s Sites or App, (2) we collect when you visit a Jenny Craig Center, or (3) from other online and offline sources in an effort to provide you with a seamless experience, better serve your needs, and provide you with content and advertising that is more relevant to your interests.

### Information Disclosure/Sharing

Jenny Craig may also disclose the personal information we collect from and about you as follows: (1) to our Service Providers, if the disclosure will enable them to perform a business, professional or technical support function for us; (2) as necessary if we believe that there has been a violation of the Jenny Craig Terms of Use or of our rights or the rights of any third party; (3) to respond to judicial process and provide information to law enforcement or regulatory agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law; (4) as described to you at the point of collection; (5) to third parties who provide educational content regarding weight loss and health; and (6) in the context of a sale of our assets or business as described below.

Jenny Craig may share aggregate, deidentified information with third parties for our business purposes.

Jenny Craig may sell or purchase assets during the normal course of our business. If another entity acquires us or any of our assets, information we have collected about you may be transferred to such entity. In addition, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, such information may be considered an asset of ours and may be sold or transferred to third parties. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to require that the transferee use personal information provided through this Site in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement.

### Security

We take physical, administrative, and technical steps to safeguard the confidentiality of the information we collect from and about our customers and Site visitors. Although your privacy is important to us, we cannot guarantee our security measures. Jenny Craig encourages you to learn as much as you can about your privacy on the Internet. 

When you enter sensitive personal information (such as credit card information), we encrypt the transmission of that information using Secure Socket Layer technology (SSL).

### Service Providers

Jenny Craig may contract with third parties to perform functions related to the Sites or App (“Service Providers”). Service Providers will have access to your information needed to perform their business functions, but may not use or share that information for other purposes. All companies with which we do business have agreed to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Statement and will not sell, rent, or otherwise transmit your personal information to third parties.

### Public Forums & Reviews

Any information that you may disclose on our Sites or App such as in blogs, on message boards, in chat rooms, or on other public areas on the Site or App, becomes public information. Please exercise caution when disclosing personal information in these public areas. If you terminate your account, we may continue to show some of your content in anonymized form.

### Links to Other Websites

The Sites and App may have links to third-party websites or applications, which may have privacy policies that differ from our own. We are not responsible for the practices of such sites or applications. Please note that if you provide any information on your own to third parties, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of your personal information. We encourage you to investigate and ask questions before disclosing information to third parties.

### Your California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident, you have a right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third-parties to which the company has disclosed Personal Information, as defined under California Civil Code Section 1798.80(e), during the preceding year for third- party direct marketing purposes. We will respond to one request per California resident per calendar year, according to California Civil Code Section 1798.83. You may request this information in writing by contacting us by mail at 5770 Fleet Street, Carlsbad, CA, 92008, Attn: Legal Department or by email at [jennycare@jennycraig.com](mailto:jennycare@jennycraig.com). In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for your response. Please allow up to thirty (30) days for a response.

### Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy

Protecting children’s privacy is important to us. We do not direct the Sites or App to, nor do we knowingly, collect any personal information from children under the age of thirteen. If we discover that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personally identifiable information without verifiable parental consent, we will delete that information. If you are the parent or legal guardian of a child under 13 years old and you believe we have received personal information from your child, please contact us at [jennycare@jennycraig.com](mailto:jennycare@jennycraig.com) to request deletion of that information.

### Access to Your Personal Information

You may sign into your account or contact Customer Service (see “If You Have Questions”, below) or your Jenny Craig Anywhere Representative to update your profile information stored by Jenny Craig or request for data to be deleted.

### Updates

Jenny Craig reserves the right to revise this Privacy Statement at any time, and may apply any changes to information previously collected, as permitted by law. If we change the Privacy Statement in a material way, we will provide notice to you by posting the updated Privacy Statement on our Site and App, updating the effective date to reflect that changes have been made. Your continued use of our Sites or App following any such change constitutes your agreement to follow and be bound by the terms as changed.

### If You Have Questions

If you have questions about this Privacy Statement or the practices described herein, you may contact us at 1-800-JennyCare (536-6922).

Effective Date: November 9, 2018
